<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guidelines on Class Homepage</title>
    <link>/docs/guidelines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guidelines on Class Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/general/</guid>
      <description>General#Attendance#Our class will be offered on campus for both Undergrad (4641) and Grad (7641). Lectures might be recorded IF class has the recording system. Any class that I am able to record [which sometimes does not work even if we have the recording system in place], I will make it available to all students (both undergrad and grad) by the end of the day. The attendance is required for both undergrad and grad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/office-hours/</guid>
      <description>Office Hours#Overview#Office hours will start on the second week of clases in a hybrid mode for both online and in-person. Please follow the instruction on this Excel Sheet [Grad|Undergrad] ​to signup for a 10-minutes slot with one of the TAs. If you require more than ten minutes, please advise the TAs. They’ll return to your Zoom meeting once they have completed their appointments with other students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion#Just as machine learning algorithms cannot accomplish complex tasks if trained on datasets of limited variability, our course cannot be successful without appreciating the diversity of our students. In this class we aim to create an environment where all voices are valued, respecting the diversity of gender, sexuality, age, socioeconomic status, ability, ethnicity, race, and culture. We always welcome suggestions that can help us achieve this goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/covid-19/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19#This semester is challenging due to the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic and a growing awareness of inequities. Please review the most up-to-date information relates to specific services and guidelines for courses during this semester at TECH Moving Forward website and in the Academic Restart Frequently Asked Questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
