<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Class Homepage</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Class Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Categories</title>
      <link>/docs/grading/categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/grading/categories/</guid>
      <description>Categories # Assignments (85%) # We have 4 big assignments in total (subject to change). Visit this course&amp;rsquo;s Gradescope site for the assignment documents. See the schedule table above for deliverable due dates.
[20%] HW1: Week 1 to Week 3 topics [20%] HW2: Week 4 to Week 7 topics [20%] HW3: Week 8 to Week 10 topics [25%] HW4: Week 11 to end. We do not release solutions for homework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection</title>
      <link>/docs/resources/collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/resources/collection/</guid>
      <description>Resource Collection # Recommended Reading # All content and course materials can be accessed online. There is no textbook for this course. All Georgia Tech students have FREE access to https://www.oreilly.com, where you can find a huge number of highly rated and classic books (e.g., the &amp;ldquo;animal&amp;rdquo; books) from O&amp;rsquo;Reilly and Pearson covering a wide variety of computer science topics, including some of those listed below. Just log in with your official GT email address, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>/docs/course-info/course-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-info/course-overview/</guid>
      <description>Course Goals # Analyze NLP techniques and apply them to text data. The course is divided into three main categories:
Preprocessing: Demonstrate how to clean and integrate text data
Processing: Apply NLP algorithms on your pre-processed data to perform different tasks
Post-processing: Evaluate your developed NLP models.
Solve problems with real datasets Apply practical know-how (useful for jobs, research) through significant hands-on programming assignments
Course Pre- and/or Co-Requisites # Review our &amp;ldquo;warnings&amp;rdquo; before taking this course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/general/</guid>
      <description>General # Attendance # This is a fully online course. Login on a regular basis to complete your work, so that you do not have to spend a lot of time reviewing and refreshing yourself regarding the content. Class Deliverables # All class deliverables will be handled via Gradescope except quizzes which will be on Canvas. The time span offered to complete the course objectives is plentiful and deadlines will not be extended under any circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instructor and TAs</title>
      <link>/docs/course-info/instructors-and-tas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-info/instructors-and-tas/</guid>
      <description> Instructors and TAs # Instructor # Max Mahdi Roozbahani mahdir@gatech.edu https://mahdi-roozbahani.github.io/ Wafa Louhichi wlouhichi3@gatech.edu https://www.linkedin.com/in/wafa-louhichi/ Nimisha Roy nroy9@gatech.edu https://nimisharoy9.wixsite.com/myportfolio Head TAs # Ruslina Utomo rutomo6@gatech.edu TAs # Faizan Hasan fhasan8@gatech.edu Ashwin Pathak apathak60@gatech.edu Mehul Soni mehul.soni918@gatech.edu Daanish M Mohammed dmohammed7@gatech.edu Ruijia Wang rwang@gatech.edu Rohit Das rohdas@gatech.edu </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/office-hours/</guid>
      <description>Office Hours # Overview # TAs plan to hold office hours starting week 2, except on Georgia Tech holidays (e.g., thanksgiving, MLK day, spring break). Each office hour session will be run by at least one TA, and is 1 hour long. See GT’s academic calendar for the full list of holidays https://registrar.gatech.edu/calendar. We will spread the office hours across weekdays, and across time of the day. We will announce the office hour times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>/docs/course-info/course-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/course-info/course-schedule/</guid>
      <description> Schedule # Important
All deadline and due dates in this course will be at 23:59 ET.
Scroll horizontally to see the full schedule table on mobile devices Astericks (*) indicate that the lecture slides/notes are available.
Week Dates Topics Homework Quizzes Project Readings 1 8/21 - 8/25 Course introduction Text data preprocessing: Normalization, lemmatization, stemming, stop words removal&amp;hellip; 2 8/28 - 9/01 Text Representations: One hot encoding BoW (frequency counting) TF-IDF HW1 out 9/01 Quiz 0 | Knowledge-based | out 8/25 - due 9/01 3 9/04 - 9/08 Labor Day Holiday Classification Introduction Naive Bayes Classification Model Evaluation: accuracy, precision, recall, confusion matrix Quiz 1 | week 1 and 2| out 9/01 - due 9/06 4 9/11 - 9/15 Focus on HW1 Quiz 2 | week 3| out 9/08 - due 9/12 5 9/18 - 9/22 Logistic Regression SVM Perceptron *Density Estimation (*Notes L10-B) HW1 due 9/22 HW2 out 9/22 6 9/25 - 9/29 SVD (Dimensionality Reduction) + Co-occurrence embeddings Glove Quiz 3 | week 5| out 9/22 - due 9/26 GloVe: Global Vectors for Word Representation 7 10/2 - 10/6 Focus on HW2 8 10/9 - 10/13 Fall break Neural Network (fully connected) Word2vec: CBoW, Skip-Gram Quiz 4 | week 6| out 10/06 - due 10/12 NN Playground Interactive NN initialization; The role of a hidden layer; Back propagation numerical example; More detailed introduction; Efficient Estimation of Word Representations in Vector Space 9 10/16 - 10/20 CNN RNN HW2 due 10/20 HW3 out 10/20 Quiz 5 | week 8| out 10/13 - due 10/17 CNN Live Demo; A guide to an efficient way to build CNN and optimize its hyper-parameters; Back Propagation in CNN; Transfer learning in CNN; 10 10/23 - 10/27 Focus on HW3 Quiz 6 | week 9| out 10/20 - due 10/24 11 10/30 - 11/03 LSTM and GRU LSTM + Attention (Focus on Attention mechanism) HW3 due 11/03 HW4 out 11/03 12 11/06 - 11/10 Transformer models Examples: BERT(Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers) and GPT (Generative Pre-trained Transformer) Quiz 7 | week 11| out 11/03 - due 11/07 Attention Is All You Need; BERT: Pre-training of Deep Bidirectional Transformers for Language Understanding; 13 11/13 - 11/17 Sequence Labelling: POS Tagging Sequence Labelling: NER Quiz 8 | week 12| out 11/10 - due 11/14 14 11/20 - 11/24 Unsupervised Models Student Recess Holiday Thanksgiving Break Quiz 9 | week 13| out 11/17 - due 11/21 15 11/27 - 12/01 Topic Modeling (Latent Semantic Indexing, LDA (Latent Dirichlet Allocation) HW4 due 12/01 Quiz 10 | week 14 and 15| out 11/24 - due 11/28 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion # Just as machine learning algorithms cannot accomplish complex tasks if trained on datasets of limited variability, our course cannot be successful without appreciating the diversity of our students. In this class we aim to create an environment where all voices are valued, respecting the diversity of gender, sexuality, age, socioeconomic status, ability, ethnicity, race, and culture. We always welcome suggestions that can help us achieve this goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/docs/guidelines/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/guidelines/covid-19/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 # This semester is challenging due to the ongoing Covid-19 pandemic and a growing awareness of inequities. Please review the most up-to-date information relates to specific services and guidelines for courses during this semester at TECH Moving Forward website and in the Academic Restart Frequently Asked Questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
